<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2022 wxMaxima Team -->
<component type="desktop">
  <id>io.github.wxmaxima_developers.wxMaxima</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0-or-later</project_license>
  <name>wxMaxima</name>
  <update_contact>wxMaxima@physikbuch.de</update_contact>
  <summary>A graphical user interface for Maxima, a powerful computer algebra system</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      wxMaxima is a graphical user interface for the computer algebra system Maxima:
      a program that solves mathematical problems by manipulating
      equations (and outputting the resulting formula), instead of just
      calculating a number. wxMaxima eases the use of Maxima by making
      most of its commands available through a menu system and by
      providing input dialogs for commands that require more than one
      argument. It also implements its own display engine that outputs
      mathematical symbols directly instead of depicting them with
      ASCII characters.
    </p>
    <p>
      wxMaxima also features 2D and 3D inline plots, simple animations,
      mixing of text and mathematical calculations to create documents,
      exporting of input and output to TeX, document structuring and a
      browser for Maxima's manual including command index and full text
      searching.
    </p>
  </description>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://wxMaxima-developers.github.io/wxmaxima/images/linux_1.png</image>
      <caption>An example of a plot embedded in a work sheet</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <categories>
    <category>Science</category>
    <category>Education</category>
  </categories>


  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/wxMaxima-developers/wxmaxima/issues</url>
  <url type="homepage">https://wxMaxima-developers.github.io/wxmaxima/</url>
  <url type="help">https://wxmaxima-developers.github.io/wxmaxima/help.html</url>
  <developer_name>wxMaxima Team</developer_name>
  <kudos>
    <kudo>HiDpiIcon</kudo>
    <kudo>HighContrast</kudo>
    <kudo>UserDocs</kudo>
  </kudos>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.wxmaxima_developers.wxMaxima.desktop</launchable>
  <provides>
    <binary>wxMaxima</binary>
  </provides>
  <translation type="gettext">wxMaxima</translation>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.0">
    <content_attribute id="social-info">mild</content_attribute>
  </content_rating>
  <releases>
   <release version="22.03.0" date="2022-03-19T22:00:00Z">
     <description>
	<p>
       Many bug fixes and improvements.
    <ul>
<li>Add an compile option "WXM_INCLUDE_FONTS", which allows to
specify, if additional fonts should be included.
Current default: YES; use -DWXM_INCLUDE_FONTS=NO when calling
CMake to disable that.
Including fonts caused some issues on MacOS. (#1580)</li>
<li>Rename command line option --logtostdout to --logtostderr.
Because the option does print the log messages to STDERR, not STDOUT.</li>
<li>A better heuristics for finding out what to style as 1D maths</li>
<li>An updated french translation from Frédéric Chapoton</li>
<li>Consistent image resolutions</li>
<li>No more crashes on exporting multiple animations at once (#1616)</li>
<li>Drag-and-Drop in the table of contents</li>
<li>Table of contents: Convert sections to subsections and similar (#1629)</li>
<li>Parenthesis and quote matching now uses the maxima parser.
This means it now both knows the details of the maxima language
and is much faster than before.</li>
<li>A way of limiting the toc depth shown in the table of contents</li>
<li>Now the problems after a kill(all) should be finally resolved</li>
<li>Better support for the debugger (#1625)</li>
<li>Machine-Float NaNs no more causes XML errors</li>
<li>Labels with hexadecimal numbers no more cause crashes (#1633)</li>
<li>wxMaxima no more skips chars in subscripted variables (#1632)</li>
<li>Merging cells per keyboard shortcut works again (#1626)</li>
<li>Symbols buttons whose symbols the GUI font lacks are now hidden</li>
    </ul>
	</p>
      </description>
  </release>
  <release version="21.11.0" date="2021-11-21T18:00:00Z">
     <description>
	<p>
       Many bug fixes and improvements.
    <ul>
<li>Allow seeing all files in the file save dialog. (#1557)</li>
<li>Fix an error when using Alt up arrow (show previous command) (#1566)</li>
<li>Rewrote a config dialogue</li>
<li>Improvements in the manual</li>
<li>Update Spanish translation of manual</li>
<li>Update German, Russian, Hungarian and Ukrainian translation</li>
<li>Fix a warning, which occurred, when starting wxMaxima the first time</li>
<li>ww898 unnecessarily limited the list of supported platforms</li>
<li>wxMaxima's properties to Maxima symbols can now no more be killed</li>
<li>Allow single GroupCells to be converted to LaTeX</li>
<li>Enable reloading and changing images inserted via "Cell" -&gt; "Insert Image..." (#1597)</li>
<li>Correctly set the document saved state when the size of an image is changed</li>
<li>Use the AUTHORS file for the Credits page in the "About" dialogue</li>
<li>Handle power events (#1607)</li>
<li>Fix ugly buttons in the sidebars with recent wxWidgets</li>
</ul>
	</p>
      </description>
  </release>
  <release version="21.05.2" date="2021-05-20T07:04:00Z">
      <description>
	<p>
	  The integral signs weren't visible or were misplaced on some MS Windows
	  installations.
	</p>
      </description>
  </release>
   <release version="21.05.1" date="2021-05-16T17:04:00Z">
      <description>
	<p>
	  Fixes a crash on printing that could be triggered on some computers.
	</p>
      </description>
  </release>
  </releases>
</component>
